# Kevin Magnan

Former police officer turned urban crime data analyst

314.303.2121

kjmagnan1s@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/kjmagnan1s

Former Police Officer during ground zero of what will be seen as one of the most paradigmatic and important shifts in policing in the recent century.

With an irrefutable interest in policing and newly acquired skills in data science and spatial analysis, seeking to leverage my experiences in policing coupled with my social science research education to participate in the juggernaut of changes fast approaching the criminal justice field.

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# **Research Assistant**

Metropolitan Planning Council, Chicago, IL, 2016-Present

Assisted the Cost of Segregation – Public Safety research team with literature review and summary, participated in research meetings and in meetings with academic and professional experts, and performed quantitative analysis using R and GIS analysis using ArcGIS

# **Police Officer**

St. Louis County Police Department, St. Louis MO, 2014-2016

Under general supervision, performed a variety of duties involved in enforcement of state, county, and municipal laws and the prevention of crime; controlled traffic flow and enforced traffic regulations; issued citations; appeared and testified in court proceedings; participated in and conducted a variety of criminal investigations; made arrests, provided support and assistance to special crime prevention and law enforcement programs such as hot spot policing; and performed a variety of technical and administrative tasks in support of law enforcement services and activities. 8<sup>th</sup> Precinct – City of Jennings

#### **Graduate Intern**

Cape Girardeau Police Department, Cape Girardeau, MO, 2013-2014

Conducted SPSS quantitative analysis utilizing department CAD (computer aided dispatch) statistical data including calls for service, officers on duty per shift, total officers, number of written reports, investigative cases, etc. for the purpose of a workplace assessment and needs analysis of personnel using federal guidelines. Benchmarked analysis with comparable regional and state police departments and presented analysis to University community and city leaders.

#### **Graduate Assistant**

Southeast Missouri State University, Cape Girardeau, MO, 2012-2014

Teacher of record for collegiate level criminal justice courses.

# Intern

United Stated Marshal's Service, Tulsa, OK 2011 Summer

# **EDUCATION**

Masters of Arts Program in the Social Sciences, Expected graduation summer 2017, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL

**Masters of Science**, Criminal Justice Administration, 2014, Southeast Missouri State University, Cape Girardeau, MO

**Bachelors of Science**, Criminal Justice, 2012, Southeast Missouri State University, Cape Girardeau, MO

Class "A" Peace Officer License, 2015, St. Louis County Municipal Police Academy, Class #183, St. Louis, MO

# **SKILLS**

Experienced in R, IBM SPSS, ArcGIS, and GeoDa

Experienced working with large and complex datasets

Familiar with policy memo writing

Effective communication

Problem solving and critical thinking

Performance under stressful situations

Teamwork and Collaboration

# **HIGHLIGHTS**

Best Overall Police Recruit and Top Academic Police Recruit

Master's Honors, 4.0 GPA

Magna Cum Laude

St. Louis County Police Officer Award of Excellence 2015 & 2016

Appointed by Missouri Governor as Student Representative to Board of Regents, two year term, Southeast Missouri State University